There are two types of people: those who would jump from a plane, hungry to feel the rush of adrenaline in those moments before the parachute opens up, and those who would rather not tempt fate, and instead find pleasure in remaining safely on firm ground, perhaps enjoying a nice view.
世界上有两种人：一种人会从飞机上跳下，渴望感受降落伞打开前那一刻肾上腺素的涌动；另一种人则宁愿不冒险，而是安全地待在坚实的地面上享受快乐，或许只是欣赏美景。
An extreme sport is one where a small mistake could result in a serious injury, even death.
极限运动是指那些一个小小的失误就可能导致严重受伤甚至死亡的运动。
What is it that separates extreme sports enthusiasts from others who prefer to avoid such activities?
是什么将极限运动爱好者与那些更喜欢避开此类活动的人区分开来的呢？
"There has to be something wrong with them."
"他们一定有问题。"
That's an assumption that many people, including researchers, have historically held.
这是包括研究人员在内的许多人一直以来持有的假设。
Why else would a person participate in sports such as base jumping and free solo climbing, which are characterised by such high risk?
否则一个人为什么要参与像定点跳伞和徒手独攀这样以高风险为特征的运动呢？
But Eric Brymer, behavioural scientist who studies the psychology of adventure, has met many extreme athletes in his career and challenges the view that they are all reckless thrill-seekers.
但研究冒险心理学的行为科学家埃里克·布莱默在他的职业生涯中遇到了许多极限运动员，他质疑那种认为他们都是鲁莽的寻求刺激者的观点。"
"Most people were very careful and took years to develop their skills," he said.
大多数人都非常小心，花了数年时间发展自己的技能，"他说。
Many don't even consider their sports risky because they spend so much time minimising risk.
许多人甚至不认为他们的运动有风险，因为他们花了太多时间来最小化风险。
In fact, a desire to manage risks was a trait identified in extreme athletes in a 2024 study called 'What factors explain extreme sport participation?'.
事实上，在2024年一项名为《哪些因素能解释为什么要参与极限运动？》的研究中，渴望管理风险被确定为极限运动员的一个特质。
The authors also found that athletes enjoyed feeling at one with nature and being part of a community of like-minded people.
作者还发现，运动员们喜欢与自然融为一体的感觉，以及成为志同道合者社区的一员。
Another theme was a drive to succeed.
另一个主题是成功的动力。
In this sense, extreme athletes might not differ much from traditional athletes – they are all united in wanting that sense of achievement.
从这个意义上说，极限运动员可能与传统运动员没有太大区别——他们都因为渴望成就感而团结在一起。
Lastly, while many extreme athletes are thrill-seekers, others use extreme sports for emotion regulation.
最后，虽然许多极限运动员是寻求刺激者，但另一些人则利用极限运动来调节情绪。
For those who struggle to confront their emotions, extreme sports can provide an outlet.
对于那些难以直面自己情绪的人来说，极限运动可以提供一个宣泄的出口。
Alex Honnold is the first and currently only person to free solo climb El Capitan, a rock formation in Yosemite National Park, from base to summit.
亚历克斯·霍诺德是第一个也是目前唯一一个徒手独攀从底部到顶部登顶优胜美地国家公园酋长岩的人。
When asked why he free climbs, he said "I'm searching more for that feeling of having done something well and being deeply content – it's more than the quick hit of adrenaline.
当被问及为什么他进行徒手攀岩时，他说："我在寻找那种把一件事做好并深感满足的感觉——这不仅仅是一剂肾上腺素。
It's personal."
这种感受其他人很难体会得到。"
You might not feel the need to free solo climb a massive rock face to feel fulfilled, but the feeling of achieving goals outside of our comfort zone is something many of us can relate to.
你可能不觉得需要通过徒手独攀巨大的岩壁来获得成就感，但实现舒适区之外的目标的感觉是我们许多人都能体会的。